<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Spells</name>
		<description>The spells from LP Mills' SEALIGHT.</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/sc-adventurers-guide">LP Mills</author>
		<update version="0.2.3">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DENNIS-TRUTHANOV/Sealight/main/Sealight/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Fascinate" type="Spell" source="Sealight" id="ID_SEA_SPELL_FASCINATE">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You perform a simple but captivating magic trick. Up to five creatures of your choice within range must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or find themselves enthralled by the trick For the duration of this spell or until you end it, the target is charmed. While charmed, the target has disadvantage on all Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks made relating to anything other than you and the trick you are currently performing. For the duration, they will have advantage on any Intelligence (Investigation) checks made against you and the trick, but they will be unable to work out how it is done. If the target is immune to the charmed condition, this spell has no effect.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">charm</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gaming set or cheat's kit</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Infuriate" type="Spell" source="Sealight" id="ID_SEA_SPELL_INFURIATE">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>	You	produce a truly irritating sound that pierces that disrupts the peace required to properly cast spells. Choose up to three creatures within range. Each target must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save,the target takes 4d4 psychic damage and has disadvantage on saving throws to maintain concentration for 1 minute.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a chalkboard and a scrap of metal</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mind Virus" type="Spell" source="Sealight" id="ID_SEA_SPELL_MIND_VIRUS">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You infect the mind of one creature within range with a virulent psychic contagion. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw, taking 6d6 psychic damage on a failed save. At the start of the target’s next turn, it takes an additional 1d6 psychic damage and up to three creatures of your choice within 30 feet of the target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be considered under the effect of this spell. The target can repeat its saving throw at the end of its turn to remove this effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">
				<em>At Higher Levels.</em> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd at the start of the target’s next turn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">psychic</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Migraine" type="Spell" source="Sealight" id="ID_SEA_SPELL_MIGRAINE">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause the brain of one creature within range to swell, causing a debilitating headache. The target must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or take 1d6 psychic damage and have their vision and darkvision reduced to 10 feet. If the creature relies on blindsight, truesight, or tremorsense, they take the damage and their sensory range is unaffected.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>